let quiz = [
    {
        question: 'STD may be due to infection of?',
        options: [
            'Viruses  ',
            'Bacteria ',
            'Protozoa  ',
            'Any of these ',
        ],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question:
            'In which age group the incidences of sexually transmitted diseases are very high?',
        options: [
            'Elderly above sixty  ',
            'Mid age around fourties ',
            'Teenagers & youngsters  ',
            'Kids below twelve years ',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question: 'Saheli is a?',
        options: [
            'A Diaphragm  ',
            'Surgical method ',
            'IUD  ',
            'Oral Contraceptive ',
        ],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question: 'What is LNG - 20?',
        options: [
            'Oral contraceptive pill  ',
            'Emergency contraceptive pill ',
            'Spermicidal Jelly  ',
            'Hormone releasing IUD ',
        ],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question: 'Which is correctly matched?',
        options: [
            'Multiload 375 - Non medicated IUD  ',
            'Lippes loop - Copper releasing IUD ',
            'Progestasert - Hormone based IUD  ',
            'All are correctly matched ',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question: 'Condom "Nirodh" is manufactured by?',
        options: [
            'Hindustan Lever  ',
            'Hindustan latex ',
            'IISc  ',
            'DRDO ',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: 'Ormeloxifene is a?',
        options: [
            'Selective estrogen receptor modulator (SERM)  ',
            'Intra uterine devise ',
            'Emergency contraceptive  ',
            'All of these ',
        ],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Which method is best to have a child if female have healthy uterus but unable to produce egg?',
        options: ['GIFT  ', 'IVF ', 'AI  ', 'IUI '],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Which metal ion released by some of the Intra uterine devises to suppress sperm motility & their fertilising capacity?',
        options: ['Ca++  ', 'Na+ ', 'Fe+++  ', 'Cu+ '],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question:
            'A couple want atleast 3 years gap between two childrens. They already have one child. What would be best method for contraception for them?',
        options: [
            'Vasectomy  ',
            'Coitus interruptus ',
            'IUDs  ',
            'Periodic abstinence ',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Which technique involves the direct injection of sperm into eggs obtained from in vitro fertilization (IVF)?',
        options: ['ZIFT  ', 'GIFT ', 'ICSI  ', 'IUI '],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question:
            "The term 'Health' is defined in many ways. The most accurate definition of the health would be?",
        options: [
            'Health is the state of body and mind in a balanced condition ',
            'Health is the reflection of a smilling face ',
            'Health is a state of conplete physical, mental and social well-being ',
            'Health is the symbol of economic prosperity ',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question: 'Increased IMR and decreased MMR in a population will?',
        options: [
            'Cause rapid increase in growth rate  ',
            'Result in decline in gorwth rate ',
            'Not cause significant change in growth rate  ',
            'Result in an explosive population/exp ',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question: 'A stable population is one which has got?',
        options: [
            'No growth of population in the last decade  ',
            'Constant rate of growth of population in the last decade ',
            'Slow growth of population in the last decade  ',
            'Growth of 20% in excess than the last decade ',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: 'Now-a-days India is under which stage of demographic cycle?',
        options: [
            'Early expanding  ',
            'Late expanding ',
            'Phase of decline  ',
            'High stationary ',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question:
            "If India's population is increasing at the rate of 13.6 million per year, then what percentage of total increase in world's population in one clender year is contributed by the Indians?",
        options: ['10%  ', '17% ', '15%  ', '20% '],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: 'The age groups in a population are classified by?',
        options: [
            'Reproduction rate  ',
            'Death rate ',
            'Age of marriage  ',
            'Sex ratio ',
        ],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question: 'One of these causes nongonococcal urethritis?',
        options: [
            'Treponema pallidum  ',
            'Neisseria gonorrhoeae ',
            'Chlamydia trachomatis  ',
            'HSV-I ',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Genital warts are due to sexually transmitted disease, spread by?',
        options: [
            'Herpes virus  ',
            'Papilloma virus ',
            'Hepatitis A  ',
            'Trichomonas ',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: 'Which of these is used to control human population?',
        options: [
            'Estrogen + progesterone  ',
            'IUCD and MTP ',
            'Tubectomy and Vasectomy  ',
            'All of these ',
        ],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question: 'Assited reproductive technology, IVF involves transfer of?',
        options: [
            'Zygote into uterus  ',
            'Embryo with 16 blastomeres into fallopian tube ',
            'Ovum into the fallopian tube  ',
            'Zygote into the fallopian tube ',
        ],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question: 'Surgical removal of testes is known as?',
        options: [
            'Testectomy  ',
            'Gonadectomy ',
            'Castration  ',
            'None ',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question:
            'The success of birth control programmes in controlling population growth is dependent on?',
        options: [
            'Use of contraceptives  ',
            'Tubectomy ',
            'Vasectomy  ',
            'Acceptability of the above the people ',
        ],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question: 'Trade name of weekly oral contraceptive pill is',
        options: ['Mala  ', 'Saheli ', 'Mala A  ', 'Mala D '],
        answer: 2,
    }
];
